<helpfile>
	<section>commands</section>
	<help>
		<name>+server</name>
		<summary>add a new server to the server list</summary>
		<args>
			<arg>
				<name>hostname</name>
				<desc>the host (or ip address) of the new server</desc>
			</arg>
			<arg>
				<name>port</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>the port of the new server</desc>
			</arg>
			<arg>
				<name>pass</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>the password to use for the new server</desc>
			</arg>
		</args>
		<desc>
<line>The +server command adds a new server to the server list according</line>
<line>to the given arguments. The only required argument, hostname,</line>
<line>specifies the host or ip address that the bot will try to connect</line>
<line>to. If no value for port is given, the default port (set in the</line>
<line>config file) will be used. If no value for pass is given, then</line>
<line>the bot will not attempt to send any password when it connects</line>
<line>to the server.</line>
<line/>
<line>Note that if you want to specify a password, you must also specify</line>
<line>a port, since the order of arguments is important.</line>
		</desc>
		<seealso>
			<see>-server</see>
			<see>servers</see>
			<see>jump</see>
		</seealso>
	</help>
	<help>
		<name>-server</name>
		<summary>remove a server from the server list</summary>
		<args>
			<arg>
				<name>hostname</name>
				<desc>the host (or ip address) of the server to remove</desc>
			</arg>
			<arg>
				<name>port</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>the port of the server to remove</desc>
			</arg>
			<arg>
				<name>pass</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>the password of the server to remove</desc>
			</arg>
		</args>
		<desc>
<line>The -server command removes a server from the server list according</line>
<line>to the given arguments. The only required argument, hostname,</line>
<line>specifies the host or ip address of the server to remove. In the</line>
<line>event that more than one server uses the same hostname, you can</line>
<line>narrow down the choices by specifying the target server's port and</line>
<line>even password.</line>
<line/>
<line>If more than one server matches the given criteria, the first match</line>
<line>will be the one deleted.</line>
		</desc>
		<seealso>
			<see>+server</see>
			<see>servers</see>
			<see>jump</see>
		</seealso>
	</help>
	<help>
		<name>jump</name>
		<summary>connect to a new server</summary>
		<args>
			<arg>
				<name>hostname</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>the host (or ip address) of the server to jump to</desc>
			</arg>
			<arg>
				<name>port</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>the port of the server to jump to</desc>
			</arg>
			<arg>
				<name>pass</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>the password of the server to jump to</desc>
			</arg>
		</args>
		<desc>
<line>The jump command disconnects from the current server (if connected)</line>
<line>and begins a new connection. If no server is specified, then the</line>
<line>bot will jump to the next position on the server list. If a server</line>
<line>is specified, the bot will search for the first matching server on</line>
<line>the server list and connect to it. If the server is not found, a</line>
<line>new entry is created and the bot begins connecting to it.</line>
		</desc>
		<seealso>
			<see>+server</see>
			<see>-server</see>
			<see>servers</see>
		</seealso>
	</help>
	<help>
		<name>servers</name>
		<summary>displays the current server list</summary>
		<desc>
<line>The servers command displays the list of servers known to the bot.</line>
		</desc>
		<seealso>
			<see>+server</see>
			<see>-server</see>
			<see>jump</see>
		</seealso>
	</help>
	<help>
		<name>op</name>
		<summary>give ops to a nick on a channel</summary>
		<args>
			<arg>
				<name>channel</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>channel to give ops on, or partyline channel if omitted</desc>
			</arg>
			<arg>
				<name>nick</name>
				<desc>nick to give ops to</desc>
			</arg>
		</args>
		<desc>
<line>The op command gives ops (+o) to the specified nick. If a channel</line>
<line>is not specified, the current partyline channel name is used.</line>
		</desc>
		<seealso>
			<see>deop</see>
			<see>halfop</see>
			<see>deehalfop</see>
			<see>voice</see>
			<see>devoice</see>
		</seealso>
	</help>
	<help>
		<name>deop</name>
		<summary>take ops from a nick on a channel</summary>
		<args>
			<arg>
				<name>channel</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>channel to remove ops on, or partyline channel if omitted</desc>
			</arg>
			<arg>
				<name>nick</name>
				<desc>nick to take ops from</desc>
			</arg>
		</args>
		<desc>
<line>The deop command takes ops (-o) from the specified nick. If a</line>
<line>channel is not specified, the current partyline channel name is</line>
<line>used.</line>
		</desc>
		<seealso>
			<see>op</see>
			<see>halfop</see>
			<see>deehalfop</see>
			<see>voice</see>
			<see>devoice</see>
		</seealso>
	</help>
	<help>
		<name>voice</name>
		<summary>give voice to a nick on a channel</summary>
		<args>
			<arg>
				<name>channel</name>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<desc>channel to remove ops on, or partyline channel if omitted</desc>
			</arg>
			<arg>
				<name>nick</name>
				<desc>nick to give voice to</desc>
			</arg>
		</args>
		<desc>
<line>The voice command gives voice (+v) to the specified nick. If a</line>
<line>channel is not specified, the current partyline channel name is</line>
<line>used.</line>
		</desc>
		<seealso>
			<see>op</see>
			<see>deop</see>
			<see>halfop</see>
			<see>deehalfop</see>
			<see>devoice</see>
		</seealso>
	</help>
</helpfile>
